♪Looking in the mirror,
my temples have turned white♪
♪Taking off the hairpins and makeup,
shedding the disguise♪
♪A cold face♪
♪With two lines of tears♪
♪If an actor could gain pity♪
♪The audience offers sincere words♪
♪Perhaps the story could be changed♪
♪The storyteller says♪
♪This mortal world is full of turmoil♪
♪Within sight but beyond reach♪
♪Yet I still don't want to give up♪
♪Don't let the memory be hollowed out♪
♪Don't make me ridiculous♪
♪Some vows turn into smoke
and fade away♪
♪Even the leaves know when autumn comes,
but you don't even know me♪
♪Imprisoned in plight,
yet still full of passion♪
♪I mock this absurd and entangled love♪
♪How can I bear to let go♪
=Whispers of Southern Song=
=Episode 3=
Why isn't Mr. Hu back yet?
He probably snuck off
to some maid's room.
♪A riot of colors on the walls,
bright and low♪
Stop.
Now...
Isn't it Mr. Rong's turn to perform now?
Why isn't he here yet?
(It seems Rong Xiaonan really fled.)
(I shed your blood on my blade.)
(The real play is about to begin.)
Where is Rong Xiaonan?
What is this?
What game are you playing with me?
(Mr. Rong?)
Switching roles.
It seems
they put some thought into this.
Sir!
You're startling the guests.
What's going on?
Mr. Hu is found dead
in the Young Marshal's room.
What?
(He didn't flee, so he can frame me.)
(Let this drop of blood
be the first offering to Master.)
(For the massacre of the whole troupe,
I will make you all pay in blood.)
The guards have surrounded the mansion.
No one is allowed in or out.
Everyone inside is ordered to stay put.
No one can move around.
Mr. Qian,
rest assured.
I will definitely find the murderer.
As long as the murderer is still
in here, they will never escape.
He died in your room.
During the noon banquet,
you were the only one absent.
You Xiaosheng Society
don't have a say in here.
If you want to kill me,
you should first know your place.
It wasn't Young Marshal.
I heard someone singing.
He was probably drawn there
by the sound of opera singing.
It was him.
No.
It wasn't Mr. Rong.
We've been together all the time.
He couldn't kill anyone.
Take Miss Jiang away.
- Yes!
Don't touch me! Let go of me!
It wasn't Mr. Rong.
- It's fine.
- Not him.
- Mr. Rong.
- Go.
Adjutant Sun,
when exactly did you hear
the opera singing?
At his...
Just tell the truth.
What tricks are you pulling?
No matter who did it,
a man of Xiaosheng Society died here,
so everyone present
will be buried with him.
(He dared kill someone
from Xiaosheng Society?)
You want to save him?
If we want to recover
the Jade Buddha Head, he can't die yet.
Now that the Xiaosheng Society people
died in the mansion,
neither of us can escape the blame.
If you don't want to be buried with him,
this is the only way out.
Escort these two guests
out of the Governor Mansion,
to the bandits outside the city.
Make it clean and quick.
Yes.
If anyone spreads a word
of what happened today,
I bet you know the consequences.
It was made
to look like a bandit ambush.
Those bandits were dealt with as well.
The deaths
of those two Xiaosheng Society men
caused me trouble, but helped cover up
the theft of the Jade Buddha Head.
Did you find the Jade Buddha Head?
I have failed you.
We've thoroughly searched every place
Rong Huaiqiu visited, but found nothing.
I have some suspicions.
The artifacts in this chest
were tampered with earlier.
I investigated. It seems Young Marshal
once visited the west wing rooms.
He has been in frequent contact
with Rong Xiaonan.
Considering all these recent incidents,
I suspect the theft
of the Jade Buddha Head
might have been connected
to Young Marshal all along.
Should we arrest Rong Xiaonan
and interrogate him thoroughly?
No need.
Rather than alerting them, it's better
to let them dig their own graves.
It's a dog I raised with my own hands.
I really don't want to kill him yet.
In the vision, Master called
the murderer "Lackey".
But today,
judging by how Xu You'an
treated the Xiaosheng Society,
he doesn't seem
to be conspiring with them.
Could it be that the one
who murdered Master isn't Xu You'an?
♪As if it were fate♪
♪Deliberately playing tricks♪
♪We miss each other♪
♪Creating a turbulent drama♪
♪And a bizarre♪
♪Anonymous legend♪
♪The plot twists and turns♪
♪Play out over and over again♪
♪Waiting to be discarded♪
♪And you are like a moth to the flame♪
♪Refuse to submit♪
♪I can't bear to blame you♪
♪There are always too many♪
♪Helpless situations♪
♪Overwhelmed by time♪
♪Even if I have questions♪
♪I harbor desires♪
♪Nowhere to find answers♪
♪People come and go♪
♪I'm still all alone♪
♪Wandering around♪
♪Fortunate to have you with me♪
♪Go through the entanglement♪
♪If longing♪
♪Turns into dust and smoke♪
♪How can I be at ease♪
♪Having walked through prosperous times♪
♪And travelled around the world♪
♪Scars all over me♪
♪If longing never fades♪
♪Burns still hot♪
♪Let it turn into dust and smoke♪
♪After half a lifetime of loneliness♪
♪In the next life♪
♪Entangle with you again♪